ARJUN **K**HAKH

Wolverhampton, WV13 3HD Email: arjunkhakh@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/arjun-khakh-117757225 | GitHub: www.github.com/arjunkhakh | Portfolio: https://arjunkhakh.github.io/React-Portfolio/

SUMMARY

Computer Science Background with Front and Back End Knowledge to build and design a great user experience on the web. Earning my certificate at the University of Birmingham Boot Camp in Web Development and completing my Bachelors Degree in Computer Science, I have used these skills and paved my way into becoming a professional Junior Developer. With each project I do, I aim to do my best and even learn along the way.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, PHP, ASP.NET Core, C#, HTML5, CSS, Javascript, Node.js, MySQL, React.js

Applications: Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Insomnia, Github, Git Bash, Microsoft Office, Google Docs

PROJECTS

Market Watch |

https://github.com/arjunkhakh/Market-Watch | https://arjunkhakh.github.io/Market-Watch/

- An application designed for the user to look at Companies Current Price In Stock and related Company News! I did this project with a Partner and we used HTML, CSS (Tailwind) and Vanilla JS (With hints of JQuery).
- My Core Responsibilities were mainly doing the JS side of the application while my partner had worked on the Design Aspect.

Weather Dashboard |

https://github.com/arjunkhakh/Check-If-The-Weather-Is-Bright-or-Blight | https://arjunkhakh.github.io/Check-If-The-Weather-Is-Bright-or-Blight/

- An application designed for the user to look at the weather in a chosen city with a 5 day forecast. This project was solely created by myself.
- HTML5, CSS, Javascript (JQuery and Vanilla)

Online E-Commerce For The Latest TechnoLovers |

https://github.com/arjunkhakh/Online-E-Commerce-For-The-Latest-TechnoLovers

- An application designed for the user to make GET, PUT, CREATE, DELETE Requests in an E-Commerce API. This project was solely created by myself so I had created the models, controllers and routes for this API.
- Express.js (Router), Node.js, MySQL (Sequelize), Insomnia

Energy Refined |

https://github.com/arjunkhakh/Energy-Refined |

https://energy-refined.herokuapp.com/

• An application which the user can view Renewable Energy Products. Users can sign in and view the products and Create/Delete Products for other users to view.

- In this project, my partner and I created this together and gave each other the same responsibility and tasks to design and create this application from the Front End and Back End.
- HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap 5, Express.js, Node.js, Handlebars.js, MYSQL/Sequelize, Winston (NPM Package that is used as a logger for the server).

EXPERIENCE

Medical Receptionist as an Employee Health and Beyond GP Surgeries

2019– 2020 Bilston, WV14 6AL

In This Role, I worked on the front desk as a Medical Receptionist. I would answer all incoming calls, book appointments for patients, and request many lists of medication to the doctors for our patients. I worked with a network of surgeries that had an average of 35,000 patients altogether (ranging from 3,000 to 5,000 patients per surgery).

Key Accomplishments:

- Fantastic IT skills and being able to learn software quickly (e.g. Emis)
- Giving Out Excellent Customer Services as said by our patients
- Showcasing my job to a primary school with my manager

Sales Assistant as an Employee House of Fraser

2022- present

Wolverhampton, WV1 3NN

As part of my role as a Sales Assistant, I would be interacting with customers and assisting customer enquiries in any way possible. I would keep our in-store items up to standard and serving our customers on our cash till.

Key Accomplishments:

- Keeping Up Great Customer Services which has been said by numerous customers
- Being Trusted by Managers in Helping Train New Employees Within The Company
- Participating in the Quarterly Annual Inventory Stock Take within the store

Software Engineer as an Intern WorkUp

30th April 2024– 20th September 2024 Birmingham, B4 7RQ

As part of my role as a Software Engineer, I would be creating new features within the WorkUp Application. It would differ from front-end tasks using ASP.NET Core/Javascript and back-end tasks using C# or working with Restful APIs. All tasks would be done using Visual Studio where I would be deploying these features within my own branch using Microsoft Azure.

Key Accomplishments:

- Designed and implemented new user interface components
- Maintained robust RESTful APIs and used .NET 8 Authentication
- Managing branching strategies using Check-In and performed code reviews

EDUCATION

Boot Camp Certificate: University of Birmingham, Nov-21 - Jun-22 A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.

Bachelors of Science in Computer Science: Birmingham City University – Graduated June 2024